好吧  如果没人开口那我就直说了
Okay, if no one else will say it, I will.
我们在彩弹枪方面糟透了
We really suck at paintball.
这真是太丢人了
That was absolutely humiliating.
拜托  胜败乃兵家常事嘛
Come on, some battles you win, some battles you lose.
是啊  但也不能输给
Yes, but you don't have to lose to
凯尔·伯恩斯汀那帮犹太小男生吧
kyle burnsteen's bar mitzva party.
我想我们得承认
I think we have to acknowlegde,
那些犹太小伙子还是很厉害的
Those was some fairly savage preadolescent jews.
不  我们的失败源于我们自己的无能
No, we were annihilated by our own incompetence
以及某些人没有能够
And the inability of some people to follow
-听从指挥  -谢尔顿  别再讲了
-the chain of command. -sheldon, let it go!
不  我还想说说沃尔维茨从背后袭击我这事
No, I want to talk about the fact that wolowitz shot me in the back.
我有理由的  那时你正把我们领向灾难
I shot you for a good reason. you were leading us into disaster.
我的指令清晰简洁
I was giving clear, concise orders.
你躲在树后喊"抓住那个小圆帽的男孩!"
You hid behind a tree yelling, "get the kid in the yarmulke!
伙计们  你们好啊
Oh, hey, guys.
早上好  女士
Morning, ma'am.
彩弹枪怎么样?  玩得开心吗
So, how was paintball? did you have fun?
当然  如果你觉得被自己人暗算也开心的话
Sure, if you consider being fragged by your own troops fun.
你们最好把日程空出来...我会提出质询的
You clear space on your calendar-- there will be an inquiry.
好吧
Ok...
周六我要开个派对
I'm having a party on saturday,
你们如果有空就来吧
So if you are around, you should come on by.
-派对?  -是啊
A party? yeah.
一个..."男女"派对?
A... "boy-girl" party?
男生会有的
Well, there will be boys
女生也是有的  而且这是一场派对  所以...
And there will be girls and it is a party, so...
我会邀请一大帮朋友  喝点啤酒  跳跳舞
It'll be a bunch of my friends. we'll have some beer, a little dancing.
-跳舞?  -这样  潘妮...
-dancing? -yeah, I don't know, Penny...
-事实上  我们不...  -不  我们...
-the thing is, we're not... -no, we're really more of a...
但还是谢谢了  谢谢你想到我们
But thanks. thanks for thinking of us.
你们确定?  来嘛  这可是万圣节
Are you sure? Come on, it's Halloween.
万圣节派对?
A Halloween party?
穿着化装服的?
As in... costumes?
是啊
Well, yeah.
有主题吗
Is there a theme?
有啊  万圣节
Yeah, Halloween.
是的  不过服装是任意的  还是有风格限制的?
Yes, but are the costumes random, or genre-specific?
跟往常一样  我没听懂
As usual, I'm not following.
他是问我们能不能打扮成科幻片里的人
He's asking if we can come as anyone from science fiction, fantasy...
-当然  -漫画?
-sure. -comic books?
-可以  -动画?
Fine. anime?
-当然  -电视  电影
Of course. tv, film,
DVD  日式漫画  希腊神  罗马神  古挪威神...
D-and-d, manga, greek gods, roman gods, norse gods--
什么都行!  可以了吗
Anything you want! okay?
什么都行
Any costume you want.
再见
Bye.
先生们  找缝纫机去
Gentlemen, to the sewing machines.
我进来了
I'll get it.
哦  不
Oh, no.
给全世界速度最快的人让路!
Make way for the fastest man alive!
哦  不
Oh, no.
看  这就是为什么我要开会讨论服装
See, this is why I wanted to have a costume meeting.
我们都有其它服装  我们可以改嘛
We all have other costumes. We can change.
或者我们可以一整晚都一个挨一个地走
Or we could walk right behind each other all night
看起来就会像一个走得特别快的人
And look like one person going really fast.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
这是男女派对  闪电侠得单独行动
It's a boy-girl party, this flash runs solo.
好吧  要不这样  我们都不做闪电侠  大家都换服装  同意?
Ok.How about this? nobody gets to be the flash. we all change. agreed?
同意
Agreed.
我要做弗拉多!("指环王"中人物)
I call frodo!
该死!
Damn!
抱歉我迟到了  我的榔头卡在公交车门里了
Sorry I'm late, but my hammer got stuck in the door on the bus.
你扮托尔?
You went with thor?
怎么  印度人就不能扮古挪威神吗
What, just because I'm indian I can't be a norse god?
"不不  你只能做印度神"
"no, no, raj has to be an indian god."
这是种族歧视
That's racism.
我是说  看看沃尔维茨
I mean look at wolowitz.
他不是英格兰人  但他打扮成了彼得·潘
He's not english, but he's dressed like peter pan.
谢尔顿既不是声音也不是光
Sheldon is neither sound nor light,
但他很显然是多普勒效应
But he's obviously the doppler effect.
我不是彼得·潘
I'm not peter pan.
我是罗宾汉
I'm robin hood.
真的?  我觉得是彼得·潘
Really? because I sawpeter pan,
而且你穿的很像凯西·瑞比(演过彼得·潘的演员)
And you're dressed exactly like cathy rigby.
她比你大一号  但样子基本差不多  伙计
She was a little bigger than you, but it's basically the same look, man.
谢尔顿  在去派对之前我要跟你谈一下
There's something I want to talk to you about before we go to the party.
我不管会不会有人看出来
I don't care if anybody gets it.
我一定要穿成多普勒效应
I'm going as the doppler effect.
-不是这个  -如果必要的话  我可以现场演示
-no, it's not that. -if I have to, I can demonstrate.
太棒了
Terrific.
这场派对是我的第一次机会  让潘妮看到
This party is my first chance for Penny to see me
融入她社交圈中的我
In the context of her social group,
我希望你今晚别让我出丑
And I need you not to embarrass me tonight.
你说让你出丑是什么意思?
What exactly do you mean by embarrass you?
比如说  今晚
For example, tonight,
没必要让人知道我的中间名是里克
No one needs to know that my middle name is Leakey.
但这没什么好丢脸的
But there's nothing embarrassing about that.
你爸爸与那个伟大的人类学家路易斯·里克一起工作
Your father worked with Louis Leakey, a great anthropologist.
这跟你的尿床一点关系也没有
It had nothing to do with your bed-wetting.
我要说的只是这是一个大好机会
All I'm saying is that this party is the perfect opportunity
让潘妮看到我成了她社交圈中的一员
For Penny to see me as a member of her peer group,
我们可能会成为好朋友  或者更进一步
A potential close friend, and perhaps more,
我不想看起来像个呆子
And I don't want to look like a dork.
注意了  伙计们
Just a heads up, fellas.
如果谁交了好运  我的箭筒里有一打避孕套
If anyone gets lucky, I've got a dozen condoms in my quiver.
你们好  伙计们
Hey, guys.
你好  抱歉我们迟到了
Hey. sorry we're late.
迟到?  现在才7:05
Late? it's 7:05.
你说派对七点钟开始
You said the party starts at 7:00.
是啊  可是通常你说七点开始的话
Yeah, I mean, when you start a party at 7:00,
你知道  没有人会七点钟就来的
No one shows up at, you know, 7:00.
现在是7:05
It's 7:05.
是啊  是啊
Yes. yes, it is.
好吧  那么  进来吧
Okay. well, um, come on in.
那么  女生们都在洗手间?
So, what, are all the girls in the bathroom?
很有可能  不过是在她们自己家的
Probably, but in their own homes.
那么服装展示什么时候开始?
So, what time does the costume parade start?
展示?
The parade?
是啊  这样评委们就能颁发最佳服装颁奖
Yeah, so the judges can give out the prizes for best costume.
你知道  最恐怖奖  最真实奖
You know, most frightening, most authentic,
最佳科学原理视觉化奖
Most accurate visualization of a scientific principal.
谢尔顿  很抱歉
Oh, Sheldon, I'm sorry,
但是不会有展示  评委或者奖品的
But there aren't going to be any parades or judges or prizes.
这场派对会很糟糕的
This party is just going to suck.
不!  拜托  会很有趣的
No! come on, it's going to be fun,
你们看上去那么棒  看你  托尔
And you all look great. I mean, look at you, thor,
还有...
And, oh,
彼得·潘  这太可爱了
Peter pan. that's so cute.
-事实上  他是罗宾汉  -我是彼得·潘
-actually, he's robin hood. -i'm peter pan.
我还带了一把有你名字的魔法粉
And I got a handful of pixie dust with your name on it.
你不是吧
No, you don't.
谢尔顿扮的是什么?
What's Sheldon supposed to be?
他扮的是多普勒效应
He's the doppler effect.
这是由于波源和观察者之间的相对运动
Yes. it's the apparent change in the frequency of a wave
而引起的波频率的明显变化
Caused by relative motion between the source of the wave and the observer.
当然  我明白了  多普勒效应
Oh, sure, I see it now. the doppler effect.
好吧  我要去洗澡了
All right, I got to shower.
你们...自己好好玩
You guys... make yourselves comfortable.
好的
Ok.
看到了吧?  其他人能明白的
See? people get it.
我用奥丁(北欧神话中的主神)的胡子起誓  这太好吃了
By odin's beard, this is good chex mix.
不了  谢谢  有花生
No, thanks. peanuts.
穿这么紧我可不能变胖
I can't afford to swell up in these tights.
我不明白
I'm confused.
没有服装展示的话  我们在这干嘛
If there's no costume parade, what are we doing here?
进行社交活动  认识一些新的人
We're socializing, meeting new people.
用传心术?
Telepathically?
嗨  你什么时候来的?
Oh, hey, when did you get here?
潘妮那件猫女服是我见过最丑的
Penny is wearing the worst catwoman costume I've ever seen.
连哈莉·贝瑞的都不如
And that includes halle berry's.
她不是猫女  就是只普通猫
She's not catwoman. she's just a generic cat.
这种糟糕装扮的产生
And that's the kind of sloppy costuming
就是因为缺乏规定和竞争
Which results from a lack of rules and competion.
伙计们  看看那个性感的小护士
Hey, guys, check out the sexy nurse.
我相信是时候采取行动了
I believe it's time for me to turn my head and cough.
你要怎么做
What is your move?
我要采用镜子战术
I'm going to use the mirror technique.
她理头发  我也理头发
She brushes her hair back, I brush my hair back...
她耸肩  我也耸肩  潜意识里她就会想
She shrugs, I shrug. subconsciously she's thinking,
"我们是同步的  我们属于彼此"
"we're in sync. we belong together."
你从哪学的这一套?
Where do you get this stuff?
心理学期刊  国际性研究
You know, psychology journals, internet research,
而且在vh-1有个好节目教你怎么追女孩
And there's this great show on vh-1 about how to pick up girls.
我要是像他那么自信就好了
If only I had his confidence.
我跟女人说话都很困难
I have such difficulty speaking to women,
呆在女人身边也是...
Or around women...
有时还包括阴柔的男人
Or at times even effeminate men.
如果这个听诊器好用的话
If that's a working stethoscope,
也许你想听听我击鼓一样的心跳声?
Maybe you'd like to hear my heart skip a beat?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
不  认真的  我有短期原发性心律不齐
No, seriously, you can. I have transient idiopathic arrhythmia.
我想了解潘妮的朋友  我只是...
I want to get to know Penny's friends, I just...
我不知道该怎么跟她们说话
I don't know how to talk to these people.
我可能会帮上忙
Well, I actually might be able to help.
怎么帮?
How so?
像珍·古德观察黑猩猩一样
Like jane goodall observing the apes,
我发现一开始她们的行动是混乱无序的
I initially saw their interactions as confusing and unstructured.
但是慢慢就有章可循了
But patterns emerge.
她们有自己独特的语言
They have their own language, if you will.
继续
Go on.
新来的人接近一伙已经在聊的人
It seems that the newcomer approaches the existing group
然后说"看我都神志不清了"
With the greeting, "how wasted am i?"
接着就有一阵类似"伙计"这样的欢迎声
Which is met with an approving chorus of "dude."
然后呢?
Then what happens?
我就只观察到这些
That's as far as I've gotten.
这太可笑了
This is ridiculous.
-我要去插话了  -好运
-i'm jumping in. -good luck.
不  你跟我一起去
No, you're coming with me.
我可不这么想
Oh, I hardly think so.
拜托
Come on.
你不是怕我让你出丑么?
Aren't you afraid I'll embarrass you?
是的  但我需要一个翼人(指要人陪同)
Yes; but I need a wing man.
好吧  但是如果我们非要用飞行做隐喻的话
All right, but if we're going to use flight metaphors,
我更适合做联邦航空局事故分析处的人
I'm much more suited to being the guy from the faa analyzing wreckage.
- 你们好  -你好
Hi. Hi. Hello.
你们扮的是什么?
So what are you supposed to be?
-我?  -我给你个暗示
Me? I'll give you a hint.
玩具火车?
A choo-choo train?
接近了
Close!
一辆大脑有病的玩具火车?
A brain damaged choo-choo train?
看我都神志不清了
How wasted am i?
我还是不明白
I still don't get it.
我是多普勒效应
I'm the doppler effect.
如果这是一种学习障碍的话
If that's some sort of learning disability,
我想这可真够迟钝的
I think it's very insensitive.
为什么不跟人说你是只斑马呢?
Why don't you just tell people you're a zebra?
为什么不跟人说你是七个小矮人之一?
Why don't you just tell people you're one of the seven dwarves?
因为我是弗拉多
Because I'm frodo.
是啊  很好  因为我是多普勒效应
Yes, well, I'm the doppler effect.
-不  不  -怎么?
-oh, no. -what?
那是潘妮的前男友
That's Penny's ex-boyfriend.
你觉得他来这里干嘛
What do you suppose he's doing here?
除了扰乱本地的重力场之外?
Besides disrupting the local gravity field.
如果他再健壮一点  月亮都会绕他运行
If he were any bigger, he'd have moons orbiting him.
呦  正是
Oh, snap.
那么我猜我们该走了
So, I guess we'll be leaving now.
为什么我们要走?
Why should we leave?
是他闯进了派对  潘妮根本不想他来
For all we know he crashed the party and Penny doesn't even want him here.
你还有一个替补的假设么?
You have a backup hypothesis?
也许他们只是想做朋友
Maybe they want to be friends.
或许是她想做朋友
Or maybe she wants to be friends
而他想要的不只如此
And he wants something more.
那么他和我就是站在同一高度的
Then he and I are on equal ground.
是啊  但是你比他更接近地面
Yes, but you're much closer to it than he is.
听着  如果这是1万5千年以前
Look, if this was 15,000 years ago,
凭他的体型和力量
By virtue of his size and strength,
科特想挑哪个女人都可以
Kurt would be entitled to his choice of female partners.
还有男人  动物  大号原始茄子
And male partners, animal partners, large primordial eggplants--
几乎所有他想要的东西
Pretty much whatever tickled his fancy.
但是我们的社会已经发生了角色转换
Yes, but our society has undergone a paradigm shift.
在信息时代  谢尔顿
In the information age,Sheldon.
你我才是优等男性
You and I are the alpha males.
-我们不应该退缩  -正是
-we shouldn't have to back down. -true.
你为什么不给他发个短信看他是否退缩?
Why don't you text him that and see if he backs down?
不
no.
我要当面维护我的地位
I'm going to assert my dominance face-to-face.
当面?  你要等他坐下来吗
Face-to-face? are you going to wait for him to sit down,
或者你要站在咖啡桌上?
Or are you going to stand on the coffee table?
你好  潘妮  你好  科特
Hello, Penny. hello, Kurt.
伙计们  玩得开心吗
Hey, guys, are you having a good time?
根据人们对我服装的反应
Given the reaction to my costume,
这场派对是对美国教育体制的严厉控诉
This party is a scathing indictment of the american education system.
怎么  你是只斑马  对吗
What, you're a zebra, right?
又一个低能儿童
Yet another child left behind.
你是什么  精灵吗?
What are you supposed to be, an elf?
不  我扮的是哈比人
No, I'm a hobbit.
有什么区别?
What's the difference?
哈比人是居住在中土世界  生命有限的矮人
A hobbit is a mortal halfling inhabitant of middle earth,
而精灵是一种永生的高大战士
Whereas an elf is an immortal, tall warrior.
那你为什么要做哈比人?
So why the hell would you want to be a hobbit?
因为他既不高大也不会永生
Because he's neither tall nor immortal
而我们没人可以做闪电侠
And none of us could be the flash.
好吧  不管怎样  你为什么不走开呢?
Well, whatever. why don't you go hop off on a quest?
我在跟潘妮说话
I'm talking to penny here.
我想我们都在跟潘妮说话
I think we're all talking to penny here.
我没有  无意冒犯
I'm not. no offense.
好吧  也许你没听到
Okay, maybe you didn't hear me.
-走开  -别这样  科特  友好点
-go away. -all right, Kurt, be nice.
我很友好
Oh, I am being nice.
对吧  小兄弟?
Right, little buddy?
-科特  -好吧
Kurt. Ok.
我明白你企图用武力恐吓我
I understand your impulse to try to physically intimidate me.
我是说  你在智力水准上没法跟我比
I mean, you can't compete with me on an intellectual level
所以你被迫只能变得像动物似的
So you're driven to animalistic puffery.
你说我是只动物?
You calling me a puffy animal?
当然没有  没有  他没有
Of course not. no, he's not.
你没有  是吧  里奥纳德?
You're not, right, Leonard?
没有  我是说"动物似的"
No, I said "animalistic."
当然  我们都是动物  但是
Of course we're all animals, but,
我们中有些人在进化树上爬得更高一点
Some of us have climbed a little higher on the evolutionary tree.
如果他听明白了  你就有麻烦了
If he understands that, you're in trouble.
你是说我没进化了?
So, what, I'm unevolved?
你有麻烦了
You're in trouble.
作为一个侏儒  你用的词还真够大的
You use a lot of big words for such a little dwarf.
科特  拜托
Okay, Kurt, please.
潘妮  没关系  我可以解决
Penny. It's okay. I can handle this.
我不是侏儒
I am not a dwarf,
我是哈比人
I'm a hobbit.
哈比人
A hobbit.
你大脑海马区里坏掉的神经元
Are misfiring neurons in your hippocampus preventing
阻碍了短期到长期记忆的转换吗
The conversion from short-term to long-term memory?
好吧  现在你惹火我了
Okay, now you're starting to make me mad.
一个发现自己拇指的人猿会说什么?
A homo habilis discovering his opposable thumbs says what?
什么?
What?
我想我已经把要点表达清楚了
I think I've made my point.
是吗  那我在你尖尖的小脑袋上留个点怎么样
Yeah? how about I make a point out of your pointy little head?
我要提醒你  尽管我精神上完全支持你
Let me remind you, while my moral support is absolute,
但在肢体冲突上  我可是一点用也没有
In a physical confrontation, I will be less than useless.
不会有冲突的
There's not going to be a confrontation.
事实上  我都怀疑他会不会拼"冲突"这单词
In fact, I doubt if he can even spell "confrontation."
C-o-n...
Frontation!
科特  马上放他下来
Kurt, put him down this instant!
他先开始的
He started it!
我才不管  我要这事结束  放他下来
I don't care. I'm finishing it. put him down!
好吧
Fine.
你是个幸运的小矮精灵
You're one lucky little leprechaun.
他是个哈比人!
He's a hobbit!
我挺你了
I got your back.
里奥纳德  你还好吗
Leonard, are you okay?
我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
派对很棒  谢谢邀请
It's a good party, thanks for having us.
只是有点晚了  所以...
It's just getting a little late, so...
好吧  没关系  谢谢你们能来
Ok, all right, thank you for coming.
万圣节快乐
Happy halloween.
希望这话能让你好过些
If it's any consolation,
我认为"人猿"那句确实很适合他
I thought that homo habilis line really put him in his place.
那是什么?
What's that?
茶
Tea.
当人们沮丧的时候
When people are upset,
传统上应该给他们一点热饮料
The cultural convention is to bring them hot beverages.
好啦  好啦
There, there.
你想谈谈吗
You want to talk about it?
-不  -太好了
-no. -good.
我能说的也只有"好啦  好啦"了
"there, there" was really all I had.
-晚安  谢尔顿  -晚安  里奥纳德
-good night, Sheldon. -good night, Leonard.
里奥纳德
Leonard
潘妮
Hi, Penny.
我只想确定你没事
I just wanted to make sure you were okay.
我很好
I'm fine.
我对刚刚发生的事情很抱歉
I am so sorry about what happened.
那不是你的错
It's not your fault.
不  是我的错
Yes, it is.
那就是我跟他分手的原因  他总是那样
That's why I broke up with him. he always does stuff like that.
那他为什么来参加你的派对?
So why was he at your party?
我上周偶然碰到了他
I ran into him last week
他道歉说他已经变了
And he was just all apologetic about how he's changed.
他不停地说啊说...
And he was just going on and on and...
我就信了  我真是个笨蛋  总是相信这样的人
I believed him and I'm an idiot because I always believe guys like that.
我不想回派对  因为他在那儿
I can't go back to my party because he's there.
你不会想听这些的  我很沮丧
You don't want to hear this and I'm upset
还喝醉了  我只想...
And I'm really drunk and I just want to...
好啦  好啦
There, there.
上帝  我做错了什么
God, what is wrong with me?
什么都没有  你是完美的
Nothing, you're perfect.
-我不完美  -不  你是
-i'm not perfect. -yes, you are.
你真的这么想吗
You really think so, don't you?
潘妮
Penny.
什么
Yeah?
你今晚喝了多少?
How much have you had to drink tonight?
就是...很多
Just... a lot.
你确定你不是因为喝醉了酒
Are you sure that your being drunk
外加生科特的气
And your being angry with Kurt
现在才这样做吗
Doesn't have something to do with what's going on here?
可能
It might.
你太聪明了
Boy, you're really smart.
是啊  我是个怪才
Yeah, I'm a frickin' genius.
里奥纳德  你太伟大了
Leonard, you are so great.
为什么所有男人不能都像你一样?
Why can't all guys be like you?
因为如果那样的话  人类就会灭亡了
Because if all guys were like me, the human race couldn't survive.
我该走了
I should probably go.
是吧
Probably.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没错  就是你看到的这样
That's right, you saw what you saw.
我们在夏尔(哈比人的住地)也是这样的
That's how we roll in the shire.
就来了
Coming.
你见到库萨帕里了吗
Hey, have you seen Koothrappali?
他不在这里
He's not here.
也许被复仇者召唤去了
Maybe the avengers summoned him.
他不是漫画里伟大的托尔  只是原始古挪威神
He's not the marvel comics thor, he's the original norse god.
谢谢你的归类
Thank you for the clarification.
-我应该送他回家的  -我相信他没事的
-i'm supposed to give him a ride home. -i'm sure he'll be fine.
他有榔头
He has his hammer.
我不得不说  你太棒了
I have to say, you are an amazing man.
那么温柔  那么有激情
You're gentle, and passionate.
而且上帝啊
And, my god,
你真是个棒极了的倾听者
You're such a good listener.